■
史诗巨著 重磅回归
百度贴吧衣柜字幕组倾情奉献
■
【衣柜字幕组】
听译: Violet_Rosa  Xiadamaozi  非42  守誓剑
君临
红堡
■
【衣柜字幕组】
翻译: Barossa  玛格丽_提利尔  旧镇老翁
龙石岛
■
【衣柜字幕组】
校对: pksunking Suerhine Xiadamaozi
铁群岛  派克城
■
【衣柜字幕组】
时间轴&后期: 加文-维斯特林
临冬城
■
【衣柜字幕组】
策划: baozhenyuawabi   特别顾问:屈畅(ccxx)
绝境长城
最专业的华语冰火资料站：冰与火之歌中文维基
http://zh.asoiaf.wikia.com/
维斯·多斯拉克
根据长篇小说《冰与火之歌》改编
原著：乔治·R·R·马丁
权力的游戏
第二季 第二集
“夜之国度”
天黑之前必须收拾停当
Gotta be ready before nightfall.
收到 我正在搬
Okay, keep moving.
在山脊那边再安排个岗哨
Put a watch on the Ridge
树上也要
and the tree lines.
小子
Boy.
可爱的小子
Lovely boy.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
“尖牙”
罗尔杰
贾坤·赫加尔
某人口渴
A man has a thirst.
某人一天一夜没喝过东西了
A man does not drink for a day and a night.
某男孩可以交个朋友
A boy could make a friend.
我有朋友了
I have friends.
给我们拿麦酒来 否则我扒了你的皮
Give us beer before I skin you.
某人无法挑选同伴
A man does not choose his companions.
这两个人 他们没有礼貌
These two, they have no courtesy.
某人必须请求原谅
A man must ask forgiveness.
你叫阿利
You're called Arry?
此人很荣幸是贾昆·赫加尔
This man has the honor to be Jaqen H'ghar,
从自由贸易城市罗拉斯而来——
once of the free city of--
（罗尔杰）嘿 你这小王八蛋
Beer, you little shit.
给我们拿麦酒来！
Get us beer!
你应该好好说
You should have asked nicely.
啊！
Aah!
你过来啊！我要拿那根棍子插你屁眼
Come closer and I'll shove that stick
活活干死你！
up your bunghole and fuck you bloody.
男孩很勇敢 但不理智
A boy has more courage than sense.
过来啊！
Come here!
尤伦叫我们不准靠近那三人
Yoren said none of us were to go near those three.
快过来！   他们吓不倒我
- Come here!  - They don't scare me.
那你就是笨蛋
Then you're stupid.
我可吓死了
They scare me.
金袍子来离君临这么远的地方做什么？
What are Gold Cloaks doing so far from King's Landing?
你干嘛？   他们在找我
- What are you doing?  - They're looking for me.
这里你负责吗？
You in command here?
你们离家可够远的
You're a long way from home.
尤伦
我刚刚问你话呢
I asked you a question.
是  你是问了
Aye, you did.
但是你态度太差
You asked without manners
所以我不想回答
and I chose not to answer.
我奉王家授权状
I have a royal warrant
要拿你手下的某只阴沟鼠
for one of these gutter rats you're transporting.
问题在于
Well, the thing is...
这群阴沟鼠现在是咱守夜人的人了
These gutter rats belong to the Night's Watch.
国王和太后可管不到那么远
Now, that puts them beyond the reach of Kings and Queens.
是么？
Does it?
这可真有趣
It's a funny thing--
人们往往太过注重保护喉咙
people worry so much about their throats
结果忽视了来自下方的威胁
that they forget about what's down low.
这把刀子我早餐之前才刚刚磨过
Now I sharpened this blade before breakfast.
如果我愿意 用来刮蜘蛛屁股上的毛都行
I could shave a spider's arse if I wanted to
或者 我可以用它割开你腿上的动脉
or I could nick this artery in your leg.
割了之后 这附近可没人知道
And once it's nicked, there's no one around here
如何给动脉止血
who knows how to unnick it.
这东西咱们就替你保管了
We'll just keep that.
长城上总是需要好钢
Good steel is always needed on the Wall.
看起来你似乎得做个选择
Seems you have a choice--
要么死在这个远离家乡的十字路口
you can die here at this crossroads a long way from home,
要么滚回城 告诉你的头儿
or you can go back to your city and tell your Masters
你没找到要找的东西
you didn't find what you were looking for.
我们正在找一个叫詹德利的男孩
We're looking for a boy named Gendry.
他带着一顶牛头盔
He carries a bull's head helmet.
谁把他交上来 就能得到国王的赏赐
Anyone turning him over will earn the King's reward.
我们还会带着更多的人回来
We'll be back with more men
到时候我要把你的脑袋和那男孩一起带走
and I'll be taking your head home along with that bastard boy.
瓦里斯
雪伊
大人
My Lord.
你让我等了太久
You make me wait a long time,
还好你的朋友一直在陪我
but your friend keeps me company.
我们刚刚在谈论您如何英勇无敌
We were just speaking of your bravery
大败史塔克军
in the victory against the Stark auxiliary forces.
那可是一场大战
It was quite a battle.
我听说您的脑袋受了严重的伤哟
I heard you suffered a terrible head wound.
那群北方人可真是些令人畏惧的战士
The northerners are such fearsome warriors.
我还给他讲了我们相遇的故事
And I tell him the story of how we meet.
关于您是如何在父亲的厨房里
To find so lovely a creature
找到这么个尤物的事
working in your father's kitchens--
我差点就信了
it almost beggars belief.
奇事偶尔也会发生
Strange things do happen.
你该尝尝她的鱼肉“饼”儿
You should taste her fish pie.
我觉得瓦里斯大人不会喜欢吃鱼肉饼的
I don't think Lord Varys likes fish pie.
这您怎么知道？  我就是知道
How can you tell?  I can always tell.
瓦里斯大人也好 我也罢
Men like Lord Varys and I can't let
都不喜欢被人提及自身的缺憾
our disadvantages get the best of us.
他肯老老实实帮我把鱼打来就谢谢了
We'll make a fisherman of him yet.
我很高兴你的新朋友
I am glad your new friend
能陪你一起来王都
was able to accompany you to the capital.
朋友可是生活中不可或缺的重要部分啊
Friends are such an important part of life.
不幸的是你父亲并不希望她来
Unfortunate that your father didn't want her to come.
不过大人您别担心
But rest easy, My Lord.
我可是非常擅长为好朋友
I am very good at keeping secrets
保守秘密的
for my good friends.
你在对待朋友时的谨慎
Your discretion is legendary...
我早有耳闻
where your friends are concerned.
您看我  明明您很想休息
How unspeakable of me to go on and on
但我却仍旧唠叨个不停
when all you want to do is rest.
我现在就告辞
I will leave you.
欢迎来到君临 亲爱的
Welcome to King's Landing, my dear.
这座城市因您的到来而蓬荜生辉
This city is made brighter by your presence.
我们还要出席一场御前会议 大人
We have a council meeting, My Lord.
我不喜欢威胁
I don't like threats.
谁威胁您了？  我可不是奈德·史塔克
Who threatened you?  I'm not Ned Stark.
我了解这场游戏的规则
I understand the way this game is played.
奈德·史塔克是个有荣誉心的人
Ned Stark was a man of honor.
而我不是
And I am not.
再威胁我 我就把你扔进海里去
Threaten me again and I'll have you thrown into the sea.
那样您可能会对结果很失望哟
You might be disappointed in the results.
风暴来复往兮
Storms come and go,
大鱼吃掉小鱼
the big fish eat the little fish,
而我仍旧是那个弄潮儿
and I keep on paddling.
来吧 大人
Come, My Lord.
我们不该让太后久等
We shouldn't keep the queen waiting.
"从今以后 直到永远
"From this time until the end of time
我们都不再是你们国度的一部分
we are not part of your realm,
而是一个自由并且独立的北境王国"
but a free and independent kingdom of the North."
他比他父亲更有胆 这点我承认
He has more spirit than his father, I'll give him that.
你完美的展示了撕纸的艺术
You've perfected the art of tearing up papers.
把他父亲的遗骨还回去吧
We can give him his father's bones back at least
至少展示一下诚意
as a gesture of good faith.
你会把我们的回复带给史塔克吧 表弟？
You'll give the Starks our reply, cousin?
我会的 陛下
I will, Your Grace.
你在史塔克那里作客时
Did you see my brother
有没有见到我弟弟？
when you were the Starks' guest?
瓦里斯
“八爪蜘蛛” 情报总管
培提尔·贝里席
“小指头” 财政大臣
我见到了
I did.
他们没能令他屈服 陛下
They have not broken his spirit, Your Grace.
派席尔
首席学士
如果你有机会和他说话
If you speak with him,
告诉他 他还没有被遗忘
tell him he's not been forgotten.
我会的  陛下  －一路顺风  表弟
I will, Your Grace.  －Safe travels, cousin.
你的政治手腕可真是机敏灵巧啊
You have a deft hand with diplomacy.
还有别的事吗？－今天早晨一只黑城堡的乌鸦飞来了
- If that's everything... - A-- a raven flew in this morning
关于野人的麻烦？
from Castle Black.
Trouble withthe wildlings.
这就是为什么他们被称作野人
That's why they're called "wildlings."
最近这些家伙不那么“野”了
Somewhat less wild these days.
他们似乎停止了自相残杀
Seems they've stopped killing each other
并且开始追随这个 塞外之王
and started following this King-Beyond-the-Wall.
又一个国王？现在有几个了？五个？
Another king?How many is that now, five?
我都快数不过来了
I've lost count.
总司令大人向我们索要更多的人手以防守长城
The Lord Commander asks that we send more men to man the Wall.
他大概忘记了我们正在打仗
Perhaps he's forgotten we're fighting a war.
我们没法给他任何人
We have no men to spare.
冷风已然吹起
"The cold winds are rising
复活的死人也随之而来
and the dead rise with them."
北方人十分迷信
The northerners are a superstitious people.
按总司令的说法 其中一个死人闯入他的房间
According to the Commander, one of these dead men
攻击了他
attacked him in his chambers.
莫尔蒙不撒谎
Mormont doesn't lie.
你该怎么样杀一个已经死了的人？
How do you kill a dead man?
显然烧了他就行
Apparently you burn him.
你去了趟长城  回来之后
One trip to the Wall and you come back
就开始相信古灵精怪了
believing in grumpkins and snarks.
我不知道自己相信的是什么
I don't know what I believe,
但事实就是
but here's a fact for you--
守夜人部队是挡在我们和
the Night's Watch is the only thing
长城之外的东西之间的唯一屏障
that separates us from what lies beyond the Wall.
我非常有信心 勇敢的守夜人
I have every confidence that the brave men
会保护我们所有人
of the Night's Watch will protect us all.
...要我说啊
And I said,
诸神希望我们能有点尊严
"if the Gods wanted us to have dignity,
所以不希望我们死的时候放屁
they wouldn't make us fart when we died."
...我们死的时候放屁？
We fart when we die?
我老妈
My blessed mother--
死的时候可没忍住
I was holding her hand when she left this world.
她放的屁如此之大 整个床都晃起来了
She farted so hard, the whole bed shook.
葛兰
男人有这么多的老婆实在是有些贪婪啊
Seems a bit greedy for one man to have so many wives.
两三个还不够吗？
Wouldn't two or three be enough for him?
我们可正在讨论严肃的话题呢
We were having a serious discussion.
你看什么呢？
Would you look at that?
没什么比女人走开的样子更吸引人了
Nothing like the sight of a woman walking away.
我更想看她们走来的样子
I prefer watching them come towards me.
I'm sure that's nice, too.
嗯  有个叫做紫罗兰的挤奶女工
Yeah, well, there was a milkmaid named Violet
她家的农场紧挨着我家
on the next farm over from where I grew up.
我们六岁大时就开始摔跤
We were wrestling together from the time we were six years old.
后来我们长大了  摔跤的内容...
And then we got older and the wrestling, uh...
变了
Changed.
你和她做过了？
You were with her?
做过几次？
How many times?
当然是竭尽所能
Well, as many times as I could.
真希望我也是在农场长大的
I wish I grew up on a farm.
我们需要更多的土豆
We need more potatoes.
我要再削一份土豆泥
Get another sack from the sledge.
再来点芜菁吧
Get the turnips, too.
不要！白灵  不要！
No. Ghost, no.
不要
No!
白灵 走开 去 去！
Ghost, away. Shoo, shoo!
你还好吗？
You all right?
- 他吓着你了吗 - 你不能碰我的
- Did he frighten you? - You-- you shouldn't touch me.
哦  哦  是的
Oh. Oh, right.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我只是想确认你有没有受伤
I just wanted to make sure you weren't hurt.
你非常勇敢
You're very brave.
你这是干嘛？
What are you doing?
这是吉莉
This is Gilly.
她是卡斯特其中一个……女儿
She's one of Craster's...daughters.
你好  吉莉 你这是干嘛？
Hello, Gilly.What are you doing?
山姆说你或许能帮上忙
Sam said you could help.
抱歉 山姆也知道我们不能——
I'm sorry, but Sam knows we're not supposed--
她怀孕了
She's pregnant.
我们必须在走的时候带上她
Have to take her with us when we leave.
什么？
What?
- 那真是——  - 我知道这听起来有点疯狂
- What would that--  - I know it sounds a bit mad.
这不是听起来有点疯狂 这是根本不可能
No, it doesn't sound a bit mad,it's impossible.
- 总司令命令我们——  - 我们发誓守护人民
- The Lord Commander ordered us to--  - We are sworn to protect.
- 山姆 我们不能带她走  - 求你了  先生  我求你
- Sam, we can't take--  - please, ser, please.
要跑的时候我绝不会拖后腿
I can still run if I have to.
- 这根本不可能  - 我马上要生孩子了
- It's just not possible.  - I'm going to have a baby.
如果是个男孩……
If it's a boy...
如果是个男孩 然后呢？
If it's a boy, what?
你想让我们冒生命危险帮你
You want us to risk our lives for you
可又不告诉我们原因
and you won't even tell us why?
- 你为什么要这样？  - 哪样？问她问题？
- Why'd you do that?  - Do what? Ask her a question?
- 你太残忍了  - 残忍！？
- You were cruel.  - Cruel?
山姆 你就这么急着想丢掉一只手吗？
Sam, are you in such a hurry to lose a hand?
- 我又没碰她  - 但你正想要偷她
- I didn't touch her.  - No, you just want to steal her.
你知道卡斯特为此会切掉你什么么？
What do you think Craster cuts off for that?
我偷不走她
I can't steal her.
她是个人 不是山羊
She's a person,not a goat.
我们正在渐渐深入野人的领土
We're heading deeper and deeper into wildling territory.
我们不能带着一个女孩同行 莫尔蒙不会同意的
We can't take a girl with us.Mormont wouldn't have it.
即使他真的同意 我们该拿她怎么办？
And even if he would,what would we do with her?
谁为她接生婴儿？你吗？
Who's going to deliver a baby, you?
我可以试试
I could try.
怎么了？我读到过有关的书
What?I've read about it.
读过一点
A bit.
抱歉山姆
I'm sorry, Sam.
我们帮不了她
We can't help her.
卡丽熙
Khaleesi.
-您无须目睹此事  -他是吾血之血
- You don't need to see this.  - He is blood of my blood.
- 这是谁干的？  - 也许是波诺卡奥
- Who did this?  - Khal Pono, perhaps.
也可能是贾科卡奥
Khal Jhaqo.
他们可不喜欢一个女人率领一个卡拉萨
They don't like the idea of a woman leading a Khalasar.
等我找他们算完帐想必他们会更加讨厌
They will like it far less when I am done with them.
他们杀死了他的灵魂
（多斯拉克语）
别哭了 他们杀不掉灵魂的
不 他们可以
（多斯拉克语）
他们把他像动物一样虐杀了
而且他的尸体没有被焚化
（多斯拉克语）
他将变成孤魂野鬼 无法前往夜之国度祖先们相聚
别哭了 我们给他建个火堆 补上葬礼
（多斯拉克语）
我答应你 一言为定
拉卡霍就会骑着骏马 与他的祖先相会
（多斯拉克语）
席恩·葛雷乔伊
城堡是否仍和您记忆中一致呐  大人?
Is it as you remember,My Lord?
看起来小了些
It looks smaller.
孩子的眼里  所有的东西都要大些
Everything looks bigger when you're a child.
我还记得在我小时候
I remember my father's cabin
我觉得父亲的船舱大得像座宫殿
felt like a palace when I was little.
如今你看
Now look at it.
他们会在码头上等我
They'll be waiting for me on the docks.
谁？
Who will?
相关之人呗
Anyone who matters.
今天对他们来说可是个大日子
This is a big day for them.
我离开之后他们便没什么值得兴奋的事情
They haven't had much to get excited about since I left.
铁群岛是个严苛艰难之地
It's a hard place,the Iron Islands.
一直都是
Always has been.
It's cold and it's wet.
如此湿冷
啊，我爱这湿冷
Oh, I love the cold and wet.
人们说艰苦的地方养育出坚毅的人
They say hard places breed hard men.
坚毅的人统治这个世界
And hard men rule the world.
兴许不久之后您就会成为国王
Then you'll be king before long.
笑的时候闭上嘴巴
Try smiling with your lips closed.
嗯  好多了
Better.
我父亲不信任你们铁民
My father doesn't trust you Iron islanders.
我不怪他
I don't blame him.
他说你们是掠夺者和强奸犯
He says that you're all reavers and rapers
不管你们拥有多少女人
and that no matter how many women you have,
你们永远不会满——
you'll never be sat-- !
别提你父亲了
Quit talking about your father.
他对我们的看法正确得很呐
But he's right about us.
我们铁群岛的“岩妻” 只负责给我们生儿育女
Our wives from the Iron Islands,they're for breeding.
但这无法使我们满足
That's not enough for us.
所以我们从那些抢来的女人里边
That's why we take salt wives--
挑选“盐妾”
the women we capture.
占有我吧！
Capture me.
我可以同您一齐上岸
Take me with you when you go ashore.
- 让我成为您的盐妾  - 你该待在这船上
- Make me your salt wife.  - Your place is on this ship.
您走后我怕是呆不下去了
Not after you leave.
父亲会惩罚我
Father will punish me.
他会责骂我是个妓女
He'll call me a whore.
我可没给钱你
I haven't paid you.
噢，噢
Oh, yeah.
我给了更好的东西……
I paid good money...
她连碰都没让我碰
I barely touched her.
而我付的买春钱却是寻常妓院的两倍
Now, you charge twice as much as every other brothel
我得到了什么？一直在哭！
and this is what I get-- crying.
稍等片刻 我的朋友 稍等
One moment, my friend.A moment.
请务必接受我最诚挚的歉意
Please accept my sincerest apologies.
兰卡会伺候好您的
Aremca will take good care of you.
萝丝
-抱歉 大人  -嘘
- I'm sorry, My Lord.  - Shh, shh.
他伤害你了吗？
Did he hurt you?
没有 大人
No, My Lord.
是梅玵
It's Mhaegen.
谁？
Who?
她为您服务
She works for you.
她就是那个——金袍子
She's the one--the Gold Cloaks,
- 杀了她的孩子  - 啊 是的
- they killed her baby.  - Ah, yes.
这事……
That was...
处理得太轻率了
poorly handled.
往往 那些权倾天下的贵胄
Sometimes those with the most power
是最没仁慈之心的
have the least grace.
我总是情不自禁想起这事
I can't stop thinking about it.
无法入眠
I can't sleep.
她那可怜的孩子
That poor little baby.
你知道吗？你让我想起另一个姑娘
You know, you remind me of another girl,
我曾经在某个极乐之地
a lovely thing I once acquired
所占得的尤物
from a Lysene pleasure house--
美丽动人 就像你
beautiful, like yourself,
而且 聪明也如你
and intelligent,like yourself.
但她并不快乐
But she wasn't happy.
常常以泪洗面
She cried often.
我询问她缘由 但我和她
I asked her why,but we didn't have
并不像现在我们这般相处融洽
the kind of rapportthat you and I have.
是啊 这让人悲伤又遗憾
Yes, it was quite sad.
从那些个地方来的女孩儿总是昂贵
Girls from the Lysene pleasure houses are expensive,
极其昂贵
extremely expensive.
而她没有为我带来任何钱财收入
And this one wasn't making me any money.
我讨厌失败的投资
I hate bad investments.
是的 我讨厌
Really, I-- I do.
那令我夜不能寐
They haunt me.
我不知如何使她开心
I had no idea how to make her happy,
也不知如何减轻我的损失
no idea how to mitigate my losses.
一位腰缠万贯的恩客 他给了我
A very wealthy patron,he offered me
极其可观的一笔钱
a tremendousamount of money
用那些大部分男人也从未使用过的方法调教
to let him transform this lovely, sad girl.
用那些大部分男人
To use her in ways that...
也从未使用过的方法调教
Would never occur to most men.
而大多数男人会用的方法 相信你并不陌生
And you know what occurs to most men.
我说不准最后他是否让她开心了起来
I would not say he succeeded in making her happy,
但我的损失可是切切实实地减轻了
but my losses were definitely mitigated.
今晚休息吧 为梅玵的孩子哀悼
Take tonight off to mourn Mhaegen's child.
明天见
I'll see you tomorrow.
到时你能开心点么？
And you'll be happy?
那会令我高兴的
That makes me happy.
再来点酒？
More wine?
- 该死  小子！  - 抱歉  大人
- Damn it, boy!  - Apologies, My Lord.
退下吧 波德瑞克 倒酒这方面我相信我们尚能自己动手
Leave us, Podrick. I believe weknow how to pour our own wine.
这就是你的新侍从？
That's your new squire?
你难道不能找个更体面的小子
I could've found you a proper lad.
我嘛 更喜欢不那么体面的人
Myself, I prefer the improper ones.
杰诺斯·史林特
都城守备队长
嗯 红酒不错 产自多恩？
Mm, that's a good red.Dornish?
看来您是懂酒的人 大人
You know your wines,My Lord.
那可不
That I do.
豪华的宴席 大人
A fine dinner, My Lord.
叫我提利昂就好了
Call me Tyrion, please.
如今你也是位大人了
I'm sure you're getting used to fine dinners,
想必你已习惯这等大餐
now that you're a lord.
也许我会雇佣您手下这位厨师
Maybe I'll hire this cook of yours.
算了吧 比这还微不足道的小事都可能引发战争
Wars have been started for less.
我听说某天夜里 小指头的妓院遇到了不小的麻烦
I heard there was some trouble in Littlefinger's brothel the other night.
嗯 令人厌恶的事情
Mm, nasty business.
- 但必须完成  - 对 当然
- Had to be done.  - Yes, of course.
都城守备队必须维持治安
The City Watch must keep the peace,
只不过我没意识到维持治安还需要屠杀婴儿
only I hadn't realized peace depended on killing babies.
- 君命难违  - 非常正确
- Orders are orders.  - Quite right.
尤其是太后之命
Especially the queen's orders.
我从未说过是太后下的命令
I never said they were the queen's orders.
嗯  不过还有谁想要杀光劳勃国王的私生子呢？
No, but who else would want to murder King Robert's bastards?
她一直是个嫉妒的人
She's always been a jealous woman.
你比我更了解你姐姐
You know your sister better than I do.
你听过那些关于我老哥和老姐的流言蜚语么？
You've heard the awful rumors about my brother and sister?
我不信那些污言秽语
I don't listen to filth.
那很好 不过你听过
That's good of you,but you have heard them.
我认为还是有人会信这套
I suppose people who do believe that filth consider Robert's bastards
认为劳勃的私生子比瑟曦的孩子更有资格继承铁王座
to be better claimants to the throne than Cersei's children.
乔佛里是我的国王 其余的我都没兴趣
Joffrey is my king.The rest doesn't interest me.
我感激你的忠诚
I appreciate your loyalty.
告诉我 当你的手下在王座厅
Tell me, when your men slaughtered Ned Stark's men
屠杀奈德·史塔克的人的时候 可是你下的命令？
in the throne room,did you give the order?
是我下的
I did.
即使再来一次也一样
And I would again.
那家伙是叛徒
The man was a traitor.
他想收买我的忠诚
He tried to buy my loyalty.
那傻瓜
The fool.
他压根不知道你已经被收买了
He had no idea you were already bought.
你喝多了？
Are you drunk?
我不能接受被个小恶魔质疑我的荣誉
I'll not have my honor questioned by an Imp!
我可不是在质疑你的荣誉 杰诺斯大人
I'm not questioning Your Honor, Lord Janos.
我认为你根本没有荣誉可言
I'm denying its existence.
那你认为我能在这里接受你的侮辱吗 侏儒——
If you think I'll stand here and take this from you, dwarf--
侏儒？你说小恶魔就已经很过分了 不要得寸进尺
Dwarf? Mm, you should have stopped at Imp.
而且是的 你要在这接受侮辱
And, yes, you will stand here and take it from me,
除非你想被我的朋友们“侮辱”
unless you'd like to take it from my friend here.
波隆
在我父亲从战场回来以前
I intend to serve as Hand of the King
我都将代行国王之手
until my father returns from the war.
而鉴于你背叛了上一任首相
And seeing as you betrayed the last Hand of the King,
嘛，我是在对你在身旁不安心呐
well, I just wouldn't feel safe with you lurking about.
你算老几——
What are you t--
咱上头的朋友可不会允许你这样对我的！
my friends at court will not allow this!
- 太后她...    -是“摄政”太后
- The queen herself has granted--- The queen regent.
而且你也够傻 竟然以为她是你朋友
And you're a fool to believe she is your friend.
那我们就听听乔佛里陛下是怎么说的吧
We shall hear what Joffrey has to say about this.
不  我们不需要
-No, we shan't.
今晚就有条船启程去东海望
There's a ship leaving for Eastwatch-by-the-Sea tonight.
从这到黑城堡 恐怕可是趟漫漫旅途呐
From there I'm afraid it's rather a long walk to Castle Black.
我希望你会喜欢上长城的
I hope you enjoy the Wall.
我发现它有种很特别的美感
I found it surprisingly beautiful...
一种残忍  可怕  令人不安的美
In a brutal, horribly uncomfortable sort of way.
小伙子们会将陪伴你
The lads will escort you.
晚上的街道可不安宁 我的大人
The streets aren't safe at night, My Lord.
这些人听我指挥
These men are under my command!
我命令你们逮捕这杀人犯
I command you to arrest this cutthroat.
他叫波隆
His name is Bronn
是新任都城守备队队长
and he is the new commander of the City Watch.
伙计们
Boys.
咱可是上面有人
I have friends at court,
身居高位的朋友
powerful friends!
国王亲自授予我爵位
The king himself made me a lord!
敬新任队长
To the new Commander.
假设我要你去杀一个婴儿 刚出世的婴儿…
If I told you to murder an infant girl, say,
还在她娘的怀里喝奶
still at her mother's breast,
你会什么都不问就照办吗？
would you do it without question?
什么都不问？当然会问
Without question? No.
我会先问价格
I'd ask, "how much?"
“热派”
“绿手”罗米
如果他们回来 我们还是放弃吧
If they come back, I say we yield.
詹德利才是他们要找的
Gendry's the one they want.
我可不想遇上战斗
Don't want to get caught in the middle of a battle.
我可不怕任何战斗
I ain't afraid of no battles.
恐怕还没开打 你就要吓得尿裤子了
If you got within a mile of a battle, you'd fill your pants.
我看过许多战斗
I've seen lots of battles.
-我看过...  -骗人
- I saw--   - Liar.
我看见一个人直接对别人捅刀子的
I saw a man kill another man
在跳蚤窝里的一间酒馆外
just outside a tavern in Flea Bottom.
直接捅在右脖子上
Stabbed him right in the neck.
两个人打架可不是战斗
Two men fighting isn't a battle.
-他们可穿了盔甲啊  -那又如何？
-They had armor on.  - So?
他们穿了盔甲  那他们就是在战斗
So, if they've got armor on, it's a battle.
不  那不是
No, it isn't.
一个染坊小子又懂得啥叫战斗？
What does a dyer's apprentice know about battles anyway?
詹德利是个铁匠学徒哦
Gendry's an armorer's apprentice.
热派  告诉詹德利怎么才是战斗
Hot pie, tell Gendry what makes a fight into a battle.
当他们穿起盔甲就是了
It's, um, when they've got armor on.
谁告诉你的？
Who told you that?
是个骑士
A knight.
你怎么知道他是个骑士？
How'd you know he was a knight?
呃  他们穿了盔甲啊
Well, it was 'cause he got armor on.
谁说穿盔甲的一定是个骑士
You don't have to be a knight to have armor.
任何傻瓜都能买盔甲
Any idiot can buy armor.
你又怎么知道？
How do you know?
因为我就卖盔甲啊
'Cause I sold armor.
金袍子为什么要找你？
What do the Gold Cloaks want with you?
-我咋知道   -骗人
- No idea. - You're a liar.
你可不该冒犯比你强壮的人
You know, you shouldn't insult people that are bigger than you.
那我可就没人可冒犯咯
Then I wouldn't get to insult anyone.
鬼知道他们抓我干嘛 我才不在意呢
I don't care what any of them want.
但是那些问我问题的人都没好下场
No good's ever come of their questions.
没好下场？
No good's ever come?
都有谁问过你问题呢？
Who asked questions before?
你这小人精还真是麻烦呢
How can someone so small be such a huge pain in my ass?
说嘛 都有谁问过你？
Who asked questions?
国王之手
The Hand of the King.
……国王之手们
Hands of the King.
艾林大人第一个 结果几星期后他就死啦
Lord Arryn came first a few weeks before he died,
接着是史塔克大人 几星期后他也挂了
and then Lord Stark came a few weeks before he died.
史塔克大人？
Lord Stark?
看见没？问我问题的都没好下场
See? Asking me questions is bad luck.
你估计也快了
You'll probably be dead soon.
-他们都问了你些啥？   -关于我妈
- What did they ask about?   - My mom.
-你妈是谁？  -就是我妈啊
- Who's your mom?   - Just my mom--
在旅店工作 我年幼的时候就死了
worked in a tavern, died when I was little.
那你爹呢？
And who was your father?
不清楚 让我说搞不好就是某个浑淡金袍子呢
Could've been one of those gold-hatted bastards, for all I know.
那你那又是咋回事？
What about you anyway?
你一直以为他们是来抓你的吧
You thought they were after you.
咋了？
Why?
是因为你杀了人？ 还是因为你是个女生？
Did you kill someone or is it just because you're a girl?
-我不是女生！ -你本来就是
- I'm not a girl. - Yes, you are.
你以为我跟他们一样笨吗？
Do you think I'm as stupid as the rest of them?
不 你比他们更笨
Stupider.
不 你比他们更笨 守夜人不收女生 这事谁都知道
The Night's Watch doesn't take girls, everyone knows that.
这倒是 不过你还是个女生
Yeah, that's true, but you're still a girl.
我才不是！
I am not!
哈？那你把鸡鸡掏出来撒尿啊  快点
Yeah? Well, pull your cock out and take a piss, then.
我又不用撒尿
I don't need to take a piss.
那……不许告诉罗米和热派
Lommy and hot pie can't know.
他们不会知道的
No one can know.
他们不会从我这里知道
Well, they won't,not from me.
我名字不是阿利
My name's not Arry.
我是史塔克家族的艾莉亚
It's Arya...of House Stark.
尤伦这是带我回临冬城
Yoren is taking me hometo Winterfell.
他是你爹  那个首相  那个叛徒
He was your father--the Hand, the traitor.
他才不是叛徒
He was never a traitor.
乔佛里是个骗子
Joffrey is a liar.
-所以你出身高贵  那你就是位淑女啦 -不
So you're a highborn, then.You're a lady.
我的意思是
No. I mean, yes.
我娘才是女士 还有我姐
My mother was a ladyand my sister--
你是大贵族的女儿啊
Yeah, but you werea lord's daughter
住在城堡里面
and you livedin a castle and you--
天哪 那些关于鸡鸡的……我不该说那些话的
look, all that about cocks,I should never have said--
还有我在你面前撒尿 等等事情 好囧
and I've been pissingin front of you and everything.
我该叫你我的小姐
I-- I should becalling you "My Lady."
别叫我小姐就照小姐吩咐
- Do not call me "My Lady."- As My Lady commands.
你这算哪门子的老爷千金啊
Well, that was unladylike.
奥！
Oh!
运了些啥货？
What's she carrying?
梨子和橘子
Myrish oranges,
青亭岛的葡萄酒
wine from the Arbor...
还有派克城铁群岛的继承人
And the heir to Pykeand the Iron Islands.
巴隆·葛雷乔伊唯一活着的儿子
The only living sonof Balon Greyjoy.
我
Me.
不喜欢酒
I don't like wine.
婆娘的饮料
Woman's drink.
我要去派克
I need to get to Pyke.
我会给你找匹马
I'll find you a horse.
我去那方向我能带你去
I'm heading that way.I can take you there.
就说你成
I bet you can.
你出海很久？
Have you beenat sea long?
还是你来的地方就没有妹子？
Or were there just no womenwhere you came from?
没你这般
- None like you.- You don't know what I'm like.
你可不知道我的口味呐没准你自己也不知道哟
Maybe you don't knowwhat you're like.
你需要有人好好调教一下
Maybe you needsomeone to teach you.
知道我么？
Do you know who I am?
你以为随便什么有钱人都能搭我的便车么
You think I offer free ridesto every man in jewelry,
葛雷乔伊大人
Lord Greyjoy?
把我的东西送到城堡去
Have my things sent upto the castle.
你该让我来骑
You should give methe reins.
我比你技术好多了
I'm a better riderthan you.
过去九年 我可是人不离鞍呐
I've been on horsebackfor the past nine years.
九年了
Nine years?
你还懂多少驾船之术？
Do you still knowyour way around a ship?
这双手可还有碰过缆绳？
Have these handsever touched a rope?
不必为我的手担心
Don't you worryabout my hands.
大海早已融入了我的血脉
The sea is in my blood.
如果我不看路这血脉可就要回归大海了
Your blood will be in the seaif I don't watch where I'm going.
我带了个提议带给父王
I have a proposalfor my father,
一个可以令他再次称王的提议
one that willmake him king again,
而我  就是他的继承人
and me after him.
够幸运的话 你今晚没准能留在城堡里
You may get to stayin a castle tonight if you're lucky.
这是我未来的国王的邀请么？
Is that an offerfrom my future king?
是命令 以你未来国王的名义
An order fromyour future king.
你以后可以给你的子孙们 讲述今晚的故事了
You can tell your grandchildrenabout this night.
我可不觉得这会是个适合小孩子的故事
Woman: I don't imagine it will bea story fit for children.
爹
Father.
九年了  是吧？
Nine years, is it?
他们带走的是个惊恐万分的孩子
They tooka frightened boy.
看看现在他们还回了啥
What havethey given back?
一个男人
A man.
-您的亲生骨肉  您的继承人 -这我可不敢确定
- Your blood and your heir.- We shall see.
史塔克养你的时间可比我长
Stark had youlonger than I did.
史塔克大人已死
Lord Stark is gone.
巴隆·葛雷乔伊
铁群岛大王
那你对此事怎么看？
And how do you feelabout that?
木已成舟
What's done is done.
我为你带来了罗柏·史塔克的提议
I've brought youa proposal from Robb Stark.
谁教你穿成这样？
Who gave youthose clothes?
奈德·史塔克喜欢你穿成这样 好当他的乖女儿？
Was it Ned Stark's pleasureto make you his daughter?
如果你不喜欢我的衣服 我换就是
If my clothes offend you,I will change them.
非换不可
You will.
你脖子上带的东西
That bauble'round your neck--
是用金子还是用铁钱换来的？
did you pay the iron pricefor it or the gold?
我问你呢
I asked a question.
你是从敌人的尸体上扯下来的
Did you pull it from the neckof a corpse you made
还是花钱买来配你这身美丽的衣服的？
or did you buy itto match your fine clothes?
铁钱 还是 金子？
Iron or gold?
是金子
Gold.
我绝对不准我儿子打扮的跟个婊子似的
I'll not have my sondressed as a whore.
果然不出我所料
( Necklace clinks )
史塔克家把你变成跟他们一个样
My fears have come true--
我仍是海盐与钢铁的血脉
the Starkshave made you theirs.
是吗 史塔克家那小鬼可把你当成训练有素的信鸦
- My blood is salt and iron.- Yet the Stark boy sends you to me
乖乖替他送信
like a trained ravenclutching his message.
他开的条件是我提议的
The offer he makesis one I proposed.
他需要你的忠告？
- He heeds your counsel?- I've lived with him,
我和他一起生活 一起打猎 并肩作战
hunted with him,fought at his side.
他把我当作哥哥一样
He thinks of meas a brother.
住口！不准你在这里
No, not here,not in my hearing.
在我面前说你是他的“兄弟”
You will notname him brother,
你真正的哥哥就是被这个人的父亲所杀
this son of the man who putyour true brothers to the sword.
难道你忘了你的亲生兄弟了吗？
Or have you forgottenyour own blood?
我什么都没忘
I forget nothing.
我记得我的亲生哥哥
I remember my brothers.
我同时还记得 我的父亲原本是个国王
And I rememberwhen my father was a king.
原来如此
I see.
罗柏·史塔克想要再给我铁群岛的王冠
I destroy Robb Stark'senemies for him
只要我帮他除掉敌人
and he will make meking of the Iron Islands once again.
我将亲自领军是吗
- I will lead the attack myself.- Oh, you will?
我是你的儿子  你唯一的继承人
I'm your son,your only living heir.
还能是谁？
Who else?
我吩咐过你在外面等着
I told you to wait outside.
你怎么避开守卫的？
How did you getpast the guards?
带把儿的都好骗
Anything with a cockis easy to fool.
亲爱的
My dear.
亚拉·葛雷乔伊
亚拉？
Yara?
很高兴见到你  弟弟
So good to see you,brother.
这才是我以后要讲给子孙的故事
This is a homecoming I'll tell my grandchildren about.
她不能领军！
She can't lead an attack!
- 为什么不能呢？  - 你只是个女人！
- Balon: And why not?  - You're a woman!
- 而你打扮得花里胡哨的  - 这里可不是临冬城  孩子
- You're the one in skirts.  - This isn't Winterfell, boy.
你哥哥被你那养父杀死之后
Your sister took over command of your eldest brother's ship
你姐姐就接掌了他的船
after your new father killed him.
逝者不死
What's dead may never die.
夜晚  她不是在岛上
The only nights she's spent off these islands
就是在海上度过
have been spent on the sea.
她调兵遣将
She's commanded men.
上阵杀敌都不逊男儿
She's killed men.
她清楚自己是谁
She knows who she is.
我不需任何人施舍我王冠
No man gives me a crown.
我付出铁钱
I pay the iron price.
亲自夺取
I will take my crown,
这才是我的铁种本性
for that is who I am.
这才是我们的古道传统
That is who we have always been.
你是无法独自面对兰尼斯特大军的
You won't stand a chance against the Lannisters on your own.
谁说这跟兰尼斯特有关了？
Who said anything about the Lannisters?
当我们夺下君临的国库
You'll have your gold
你就可以取走你的酬劳
when we take the treasury at King's Landing.
在所有争夺铁王座的国王中
All these kings fighting for the throne,
史坦尼斯的军队最微不足道
and this Stannis has the smallest army.
我为什么要下这么没把握的赌注呢？
Why would I bet on the man with the worst chance?
因为你是个精明的赌徒
Because you're a smart gambler.
史坦尼斯曾两次在战争中证明自己
Stannis has proved himself in war twice.
而他的小弟弟甚至都没上过战场
His baby brother has never set foot on a battlefield.
当然  僭王乔佛里也没有
Neither has the false King Joffrey.
那又如何  他们都拥有庞大的军队
And yet they both have larger armies.
史坦尼斯才刚开始集结军队
Stannis has just begun the fight.
他的封臣已经准备好响应号召
His Bannermen will rally to his cause.
七国上下
There's no man in the Seven Kingdoms
没人比史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩更具荣誉感
more honorable than Stannis Baratheon
也没人比他更值得效忠
or more worthy of loyalty.
这世界究竟怎么了
What is the world coming to
竟然需要走私贩来担保国王的诚信？
when smugglers must vouch for the honor of kings?
- 注意你的言辞  海盗  - 马索斯
- Mind your words, pirate.  - Matthos.
萨拉多·桑恩
里斯海盗
你觉得我被羞辱了？
You think I'm insulted?
我就是个海盗  而且我还是个优秀的海盗
I am a pirate.I'm an excellent pirate.
我不会为了空口许诺航行的
I don't sail for promises.
你会的
Of course you do.
每次你离开港口 你都是为了一个承诺
Every time you leave harbor,you're leaving on a promise--
在海里的某处
a promise that somewhere on the sea,
有人正抱着金子等你去抢
somebody's got some gold and you can take it from him.
- 这可是个从不食言的承诺    - 我的承诺也是如此
- That's a promise that always comes true.    - As is mine.
萨拉多  你阅历丰富
You're not a young man,Salladhor.
如果我说错了 还请你指出
And correct me if I'm wrong--
大多数的海盗很稚嫩
most pirates don't grow old.
除了个别聪明伶俐的
Only the clever ones.
你想把你海盗生涯的最后几年
You want to spend your last few years on the sea
耗在抢潘托斯乳酪商
stealing from Pentoshi cheesemongers
和弥林丝绸贩子这些事上？
and Meereenese silk merchants?
那就走吧 他们在海上等着你
Then go.They're out there waiting for you.
那都是便宜的营生
That's easy.
而我向你提议的可不简单
What I'm offering you is hard.
跟我来  去劫掠维斯特洛最大的城市
Come with me and plunder the greatest city in Westeros.
你会成为全里斯最出名、最富有的人
You'll be the richest man in Lys and the most famous.
你的光辉事迹会被人们世代传颂
They'll be singing songs about you as long as men have voices to sing.
“萨拉多·桑恩”真是太适合入韵了
"Salladhor Saan" is a good name for songs.
- 没错儿    - 有个条件  我想要太后
- It is.   - One thing-- I want the queen.
- 太后？   - 瑟曦  我想要她
- The queen?   - Cersei-- I want her.
我所有的30艘船会跟着你的舰队出发
I'll sail with your fleet,all 30 of my ships.
如果它们没有沉进黑水湾的话
And if we don't drown at the bottom of Blackwater Bay,
我可要好好地操那个金发太后 狠狠地操
I will fuck this blonde queen and I'll fuck her well.
这场战争不是为了你
This war isn't about you.
我们打君临城不是为了让你强奸王后的
We're not attacking King's Landing so that you can rape the queen.
谁说要去强奸她了  我要去睡她
I'm not going to rape her.I'm going to fuck her.
就好像她会愿意似的
As if she would just let you.
在这种事情上我可是自有一套哟
You don't know how persuasive I am.
你要不要来试试呢
I've never tried to fuck you.
史坦尼斯是唯一合法的国王
Stannis is the rightful king and the Lord of Light,
而光之王是唯一的真神
the one true God
小子 我曾经行遍许多世界
I've been all over the world, my boy,
任何我到过的地方  人们都告诉我真神的故事
and everywhere I go,people tell me about the true Gods.
他们都以为自己找到了对的那个
They all think they found the right one.
但世上唯一的真神是女人两腿间的那个玩意儿
The one true God is what's between a woman's legs,
而太后两腿间的那个更真一些
and better yet,a queen's legs.
我从没想过你还有个这么虔诚的儿子
I never thought you'd have a true believer for a son.
呃 他还年轻
Eh, he's young yet.
我保证你会拿到金子  赢得荣耀
I promise you the gold.I promise you the glory.
但我不能承诺给你太后
I cannot promise you the queen.
你对你的国王就这么有把握？
You believe your king can win?
他是唯一真正的国王
He is the one true king.
你们维斯特洛人真有意思
You Westerosi are funny people.
那家伙砍掉了你的手指  然后你就爱上了他
A man chops off your fingers and you fall in love with him.
戴佛斯·席渥斯  我会和你一起出航
I'll sail with you,Davos Seaworth.
你是我见过最正直的走私贩
You're the most honest smuggler I ever met.
让我发财吧
Make me rich.
带我到君临城门  我会的
Get me to the gates of King's Landing and I will.
国王什么时候起航？
When will the king have us sail?
待神谕降临之时
As soon as his God wills it.
那也是你我的神
He's my God, too,and yours,
但你太盲目  不能认清这一点
but you are too blind to see.
- 我来教你念书吧   - 噢 你和你妈一个德行
- Let me teach you how to read.   - Oh, you and your mother.
不会花很长时间的  你已经认识字母了
It won't take long.You already know the letters.
圣书比我有说服力多了
The holy books are much more persuasive than I can be.
我真心希望自己也能有个神来崇拜
I wish I had a God, truly.
不是嘲笑你  但我见过人们对着每一个他们知道的神祈祷
I'm not mocking you, but I've seen men pray to every God there is--
祈祷风调雨顺  祈祷平安归家
pray for wind, pray for rain,pray for home.
- 但从来没有管用过   - 但可你总能平安归家啊
- None of it works.   - But you always came home.
- 我从不祈祷   - 但我会
- I wasn't praying.   - No, but I was.
你出海的那些夜晚
Every night that you were at sea,
我总会点起蜡烛为你祈祷
I lit a candle and I prayed for you.
你想我信神
You want me to have a God?
那好吧 史坦尼斯国王就是我的神
Fine. King Stannis is my God.
他提拔我  他的信任护佑着我
He raised me up and blessed me with his trust.
他许给你的未来 远远超过我的想象
He gave you a future I could never have imagined.
你会念字   将来还可能成为一个骑士
You know how to read. You'll be a knight someday.
难道这些都是你的火神下的令吗？
You think a fire God commanded all that?
是史坦尼斯 全都是史坦尼斯
It was Stannis,only Stannis.
史坦尼斯是我的国王 但他只是一个凡人
Stannis is my king,but he's only a man.
可别跟他这么说
Don't tell him that.
杰诺斯·史林特大人是都城守卫队的队长
Lord Janos Slynt was commander of the City Watch.
你没有权力驱逐他
You had no right to exile him.
我怎么没有权力 我是御前首相
I have every right.I am the King's Hand.
你只不过是暂代父亲行首相一职
You're serving as the King's Hand till father gets here.
而我是摄政太后
I am Queen Regent.
听我说 摄政太后
Listen to me,Queen Regent.
你正失去民心
You're losing the people.
- 你听到我说话了吗？ - 民心
- Do you hear me? - The people.
你觉得我会在意那个？
You think I care?
等到成千上万的民众都想你死的时候
You might find it difficult
统治起来就没那么容易了
to rule over millions who want you dead.
凛冬来时  半个城市闹着饥荒
Half the city will starve when winter comes.
另外半个则会谋划推翻你的统治
The other half will plot to overthrow you.
而金袍子刚刚给了他们最响亮的抗争口号
And your gold-plated thugs just gave them
最响亮的抗争口号
their rallying cry--
太后滥杀婴孩
"The Queen slaughters babies."
你甚至连表面上否认一下的功夫都不做
You don't even have the decency to deny it.
不是你下的命令  对吗？
It wasn't you who gave the order, was it?
乔佛里甚至没告诉你
Joffrey didn't even tell you.
他告诉你了？
Did he tell you?
那样就更糟糕了
I imagine that would be even worse.
他做了需要去做的事
He did what needed to be done.
你想做御前首相？你想统治国家？
You want to be Hand of the King?You want to rule?
这就是统治的意义——躺在一张满是懦夫的床上
This is what ruling is——lying on a bed of weeds,
在他们齐心合力勒死你之前
ripping them out by the root, one by one,
撕碎他们
before they strangle you in your sleep.
我不是国王 但我认为统治可比这复杂多了
I'm no king, but I think there's more to ruling than that.
我才不管你是怎么想的
I don't care what you think!
你从来就没认真过
You've never taken it seriously.
你没有 詹姆也没有
You haven't,Jaime hasn't.
结果全靠我了
It's all fallen on me.
正如詹姆一再重复的 像史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩所说
As has Jaime repeatedly,according to Stannis Baratheon.
你很可笑
You're funny.
你从来都很可笑
You've always been funny...
没有笑话比得上你头一个笑话  对么？
But none of your jokes will ever match
对么？
the first one, will they?
你记得么？
You remember?
你为了降生而扯开我母亲的肚子
Back when you ripped my mother open
她因为失血过多而死
on your way out of her and she bled to death?
她也是我母亲
She was my mother, too.
母亲死了
Mother gone...
都是因为你
For the sake of you.
世间再没比这更可笑的事情了
There's no bigger joke in the world than that.
- 陛下   - 陛下
- Your Grace.   - Your Grace.
你和那海盗谈妥了吗？
How did you fare with your pirate?
萨拉多·桑恩将加入我们舰队
Salladhor Saan will join our fleet-- 30 ships.
30艘船 外加一批精兵强将
His men know how to fight.
依我来看 海盗只应付得了散兵游勇
In my experience, pirates prefer fighting unarmed men.
眼下别无选择
It does seem the wiser choice.
这次不再是选择了
There won't be a choice this time.
你信得过他？
Do you trust him?
萨拉多·桑恩是我的老朋友
Salladhor Saan is an old friend.
我俩认识有30个年头了
I've known him 30 years.
我从没信任过他
I've never trusted him,
但是只要给他钱 他从不会反悔
but once he gets the smell of gold, he never stops.
若他尽职 他的酬劳就是应得的
Well, if he does his job, he'll have his share.
退下吧
Leave us.
是的 陛下
At once, Your Grace.
光之王护佑着你 年轻的战士
The Lord of Light shines through you, young warrior.
跟上
Come.
你跟他说了些什么？
What did you say to him?
我告诉他浴火是最圣洁的死亡
I told him death by fire is the purest death.
- 为什么？   - 因为事实就是如此
- Why?   - Because it is true.
陛下 你很焦虑
You're troubled, my king.
有点
Yeah.
对光之王而言 这些军队不过些玩具
These armies are toys for the Lord of Light.
那就让你的神烧了去
Tell your lord to burn them, then.
我不能让他做什么
I tell him nothing.
我祈求他的指引并执行
I pray for his commands and I obey.
据斥候说 我弟弟有十万大军
My little brother has 100,000 men according to the scouts,
他们本该效忠于我
men whose allegiance rightly belongs to me.
你必须坚定信念
You must have faith.
信念？
Faith?
在实战中 十次里有九次都是
In a real war, the side with the greater number wins
人数占优的一方获胜
nine times out of 10.
那我们就是那第十次
Then we must be the 10th.
在战场上 我打不赢我弟弟
I cannot defeat my brother in the field.
而少了那些叛逃到他那里军力 我根本拿不下君临
And I can't take King's Landing without the men he's stolen.
我在火焰中看见了通向胜利之路
I have seen the path to victory in the flames.
但首先 你要把自己献给光之王
But first, you must give yourself to the Lord of Light.
见鬼 那些我都说了
I've said the words,damn you.
我已经烧了那些神像
I burnt the idols.
你必须全心全意
You must give all of yourself.
我可是有妻室的
I have a wife.
我发过誓
I took a vow.
她病了 很虚弱
She's sickly, weak...
独居在高塔里
Shut away in a tower.
她厌恶你
She disgusts you.
而且她什么也没给你
And she's given you nothing--
没有儿子 只有死婴
no sons,only stillborns,
只有死亡
only death.
而我将给你一个儿子 陛下
I will give you a son, my king.
一个儿子?
A son?